<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<ComponentResources xmlns="http://schemas.intempora.com/RTMaps/2011/ComponentResources" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" name="OpenCV_PointsTracking" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.intempora.com/RTMaps/2011/ComponentResources http://www.intempora.com/schemas/RTMaps/2011/ComponentResources.xsd">
<Type>Component</Type>
<IconFile>opencv.png</IconFile>
<TargetOS>OS-independent</TargetOS>
<Lang lang="ENG">
<GroupName>Image processing</GroupName>
<Documentation>
<Component>
<Alias>Points tracking</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[
Performs points tracking algorithms within the image flow.<br/>
The points to track can be provided through the second input, or can be automatically
selected via the <code>Auto init</code> action.]]></Description>
</Component>
<Property MAPSName="max_nb_points_to_track">
<Alias>Max nb points to track</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[Maximum number of points that the component will be able to track.
]]></Description>
</Property>
<Property MAPSName="auto_init_at_start">
<Alias>Auto init at start</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[If set to <code>true</code>, the component will perform an automatic initialization
of the points to be tracked when it receives the first image. In other words, it will choose which points to track.
The auto initialization is made the same way as with the <code>Auto init</code> action.
If this property is set to <code>false</code>, the points to track have to be provided
through the pointsToTrack input or the <code>Auto init</code> action.]]></Description>
</Property>
<Property MAPSName="use_auto_init_trigger_input">
<Alias>Use auto init trigger input</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[If set to <code>true</code>, an additional input will be created so that 
the auto initialization procedure will be called each time any piece of data arrives
on this input. The actual content of the data is ignored; it is only used as an event
to trigger the procedure.]]></Description>
</Property>
<Property MAPSName="threaded">
<Alias>threaded</Alias>
<Description/>
</Property>
<Property MAPSName="priority">
<Alias>priority</Alias>
<Description/>
</Property>
<Property MAPSName="spots_width">
<Alias>Spots width</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[Defines the line width to be used to draw the spots generated on the trackedPointsObjects
output.]]></Description>
<DefaultValue>1</DefaultValue>
</Property>
<Property MAPSName="spots_color">
<Alias>Spots color</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[Defines the color to be used for drawing the spots generated on the trackedPointsObjects
output.]]></Description>
<Flag name="Color"/>
</Property>
<Output MAPSName="trackedPointsCoords">
<Alias>trackedPointsCoords</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[Pairs of (x,y) coordinates in the form of a vector of integers. They represent the
result coordinates of the points tracked from the previous image.<br/>
When a point is lost, the coordinates for this point are set to (-10,-10).]]></Description>
</Output>
<Output MAPSName="trackedPointsObjects">
<Alias>trackedPointsObjects</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[Same as <code>trackedPointsCoords</code> but represented in the form of Overlay Drawing
Spots (that can be overlaid onto an image via the Overlay Drawing component, or displayed
via the Objects Viewer component).]]></Description>
</Output>
<Output MAPSName="previousPointsCoords">
<Alias>previousPointsCoords</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[Pairs of (x,y) pixel coordinates in the form of a vector of integers representing
the positions of the points as they were in the previous image.]]></Description>
</Output>
<Input MAPSName="imageIn">
<Alias>imageIn</Alias>
<Description/>
</Input>
<Input MAPSName="pointsToTrack">
<Alias>pointsToTrack</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[Pairs of (x,y) coordinates in the form of a vector of integers representing
the positions of the points to be tracked.]]></Description>
</Input>
<Action MAPSName="autoInit">
<Alias>Auto init</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[When triggered, this action resets automatically the set of tracked points with 
a new set of points whose positions are determined automatically (the algorithm
tries to determine which points are best suited for tracking in the image).]]></Description>
</Action>
<Action MAPSName="removeAllPoints">
<Alias>Remove all points</Alias>
<Description><![CDATA[Resets the set of tracked points.]]></Description>
</Action>
</Documentation>
</Lang>
</ComponentResources>
